# RADHIKA BADE

## **SUMMARY**

Data Engineer with 4+ years of experience in ETL, business intelligence and data modeling with an interest in data visualization and statistical programming. Having a record of delivering data ahead of time, that provided rapid auditing capabilities. Identified high value analysis that helped in driving better insights.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Cotiviti | Data Engineer

MARCH 2016 - PRESENT

- Involved in end-to-end process of ingesting data into legacy systems.
- Implemented stored procedures to track data quality and consistency.
- Increased 'Speed to deliver' by implementing workload/workflow automation solutions by reducing manual work by more than 20 hours per week.
- Delivered data ahead of time on many instances, that provided rapid auditing capabilities.
- Collaborated with analysts and audit teams to identify opportunities to design and implement reporting solutions.
- Coordinated with external clients to capture data requirements.
  [Tools used: Map designer, Control-M, SQL Server, Abinitio, PowerShell, MS Access]

# Marvell Tech | Business Intelligence Engineer

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2016

- Consulted with internal business users (e.g., Marketing, Logistics, Finance, and Customer Service) to develop analyses that lead to actionable insights that accelerated profitable growth.
- Wrangled data from multiple sources to create integrated views that was used to drive decision making.
- Provided interpretation, analysis and insights along with clearly stated information.
   [Tools used: Microsoft Visual (SSRS), SQL Server]

## SmarterTravel | Business Intelligence Intern

SEPTEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

- Designed and developed data models to support reporting needs.
- Performed data cleansing and data auditing to ensure data quality.
- Built scalable cubes to support ad hoc business analysis.
- Worked with various groups across the organization to make sure data required for analysis is being recorded.

[Tools used: Microsoft Visual (SSIS, SSRS), PowerPivot, Power BI, SQL Server]

#### **HSBC | Software Engineer**

AUGUST 2012 - JULY 2013

- Coordinated with internal clients to understand and capture data/reporting requirements.
- Designed and developed various Liquidity reports for the internal clients.
- Implemented workload/workflow automation solutions to increase the deliver speed.
- Programmed SQL scripts for handling partitioning and indexing efficiently reducing data load time by 10%.

[Tools used: IBM InfoSphere Data Stage, Cognos BI, Control M, SQL Server, Oracle]

# **PROJECTS**

- Explored bike vendors data to gain insights from it. Used epicycle analysis, visualized the data in R Lang and documented my findings.
- Built random forest, multiple linear regression and ARIMA models to predict Walmart weekly sales for historic data and visually analyzed data.
- Performed research on devising best practice models to determine the most suitable OLAP servers. Created cubes using star, snowflake schema; maintained and deployed them.

# **CONTACT**

**2** 617-838-4162

<u>radhikabade0602@gmail.com</u>

in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/radhika-bade">https://www.linkedin.com/in/radhika-bade</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

Northeastern University MS in Information Systems May 2015 | Boston, MA

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University BTech in Computer Science September 2012 | India

# **SKILLS**

#### **DATABASES**

• SQL Server • Oracle • MySQL

#### **PROGRAMMING**

• SQL • R Lang • Java • HTML • XML

#### **ETL**

• Map Designer • DataStage • SSIS • Abinitio • XLMiner • Talend

#### REPORTING TOOLS

• Tableau • SSRS • QlikView • PowerPivot • CognosBI • Power BI • SpotFire

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

• Windows • MAC OS X • LINUX

#### **OTHER**

• Microsoft Excel • Microsoft Visio • Microsoft Access • Control M • GRETL • GitHub • SVN

#### STATISTICAL TECHNIQUES

• Regression • Classification • ANOVA

#### **INTERESTS**

- ETL and Reporting
- Performance Optimization
- Big Data Analytics
- Data Modelling
- Statistical Programming

### CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to R (DataCamp)
- Python: Basics (Udemy)